Finding Aid for the Albertype Company Souvenir Viewbooks LSC.0983
UCLA Library Special Collections
Albertype Company souvenir viewbooks
1888-1928
UCLA Library Special Collections
Albertype Co.
LSC.0983
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303053606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of souvenir viewbooks from the Albertype Company, Brooklyn, New York, including views of the U.S., Canada, and Indians of North America.
Viewbooks.; Canada -- Views.; United States -- Views.; Indians of North America -- Views.; Albertype Co.
- Alaska
  - Picturesque Alaska., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Seals and the Seal Islands., circa 1898 (Box 1)
- Arizona
  General note
  (see also New Mexico)
  - Apache Trail., [1926] (Box 1)
  - Cactus views. Tuscon, Arizona., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Grand Canyon National park (2 editions)., 1923[?], 1925 (Box 1)
- Canada
  - Souvenir of Victoria, B.C.., circa 1904 (Box 1)
  - Glimpses of Winnipeg, Manitoba., [1902] (Box 1)
  - Souvenir of the Royal Northwest Mounted Police., circa 1910 (Box 1)
  - Glimpses of the Okanagan Valley, B.C.., [1905] (Box 1)
  - Views of Kelowna, the Orchard city ... (3 editions)., n.d., circa 1909, circa 1912 (Box 1)
- California
  - Seal Rocks, Cliff House and Sutro Heights., [1897?] (Box 1)
  - Yosemite National Park., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Santa Barbara., circa 1900 (Box 1)
- Colorado
  - Pike's Peak via the Cog Road., [1924] (Box 1)
  - The Pike's peak Automobile Highway., [1926] (Box 1)
  - Souvenir of Estes Park., circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Scenic gems of Colorado on the Switzerland Trail R.R. .... (Box 1)
  - Views of Colorado Springs and vicinity (Box 1)
  - Colorado Springs and Pike's Peak region., [1927] (Box 1)
  - Denver., 1896 (Box 1)
  - Pike's Peak region., 1925 (Box 1)
- Florida
  - Palm Beach., [1925] (Box 1)
- Hawaii
  - Souvenir of Hilo, Hawaii., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Hawaiian Souvenir calendar., 1901 (Box 2)
- Massachusetts
  - One hundred and twenty five glimpses of Boston (Box 2)
- Michigan
  - Phostint views of picturesque Detroit., 1899 (Box 2)
- Montana
  - Glacier National Park (3 different editions)., n.d. and 1924 (Box 2)
  - Views of the Mission mountains ... Flathead lake and Valley., circa 1908 (Box 2)
  - Views of Missoula ...., n.d. (Box 2)
  - Souvenir of Kalispell and the Flathead Valley., circa 1906 (Box 2)
- New Mexico
  - Picturesque Northern New Mexico and Arizona., [1926] (Box 2)
  - Roswell, New Mexico., circa 1909 (Box 2)
- New Jersey
  - Ocean Grove and Asbury Park., circa 1891 (Box 2)
- Nebraska
  - Souvenir of Omaha, Nebraska., circa 1902 (Box 2)
- New York
  - Niagara., circa 1924 (Box 2)
- Oklahoma
  - [Guthrie]., [1908] (Box 2)
- Oregon
  - Marine views showing the scenic beauty of the Oregon Coast near Newport, Oregon., [1904] (Box 2)
  - Progressive Portland., [1911] (Box 2)
  - Souvenir of Baker City, Oregon., n.d.; (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - University of Oregon., circa 1895 (Box 2)
  - Views of Hood River, Oregon and glimpses of Hood River Valley., circa 1905 (Box 2)
  - [Columbia Highway]., [1926] (Box 2)
- Ohio
  - Ada and the O.N.U.., circa 1902 (Box 3)
- Pennsylvania
  - Points of interest in Philadelphia and Fairmount Park., circa 1900 (Box 3)
- Rhode Island
  - Sixty-five glimpses of Newport., n.d. (Box 3)
- South Dakota
  - Souvenir of Hot Springs., circa 1898 (Box 3)
- Texas
  - Souvenir of El Paso., [1908]; (2 copies) (Box 3)
  - Souvenir of Galveston., [1904]; (2 copies) (Box 3)
  - Camp Wabun Annung, Kerrville, Texas., [1927] (Box 3)
- Utah
  - Ogden City, Utah., circa 1893 (Box 3)
  - Souvenir of Ogden., [1904] (Box 3)
  - Views of Ogden., [1900] (Box 3)
  - Souvenir of Park City ...., [1891] (Box 3)
- Washington
  - Souvenir of Seattle., [1901] (Box 3)
  - Seattle, the gateway to Alaska and the Orient. (Box 3)
  - Washington, the evergreen state, scenes from her exhibit at the world's Columbian exposition., 1893 (Box 3)
  - Souvenir of Tacoma, Washington., [1900] (Box 3)
  - Souvenir of Bellingham., n.d. (Box 3)
  - The big features of Rainier National Park., [1926] (Box 3)
  - Mount Baker National Forest., [1928] (Box 3)
  - St. Paul and Tacoma Lumber Company., circa 1900 (Box 3)
- Washington, D.C.
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 3)
- Wyoming
  - Yellowstone National Park, Illustrated., circa 1888 (Box 3)
- Indians
  - Among the Sioux. Photographed and compiled by J.A. Anderson., circa 1896 (Box 3)
  - Indians of the western prairie. Tacoma, Washington., 1901 (Box 3)